{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "A slave named Ben claimed to have found this man’s dead body surrounded by sixteen corpses, one of which had this man’s knife stuck in it. This man’s loss in an 1835 Congressional election prompted him to tell his statesmen that “they might go to hell, and I would go to Texas.” This man joined William Travis in disobeying an order by Sam Houston to abandon a San Antonio mission. For ten points, name this man who died defending the Alamo, a legendary frontiersman from Tennessee.",
      "answer": "David “Davy” Crockett"
    },
    {
      "question": "The 1957 Wolfenden Commission proposed eliminating laws punishing this crime. The Labouchere Amendment led to an imprisonment in Reading Gaol [”redding jail”] for committing this crime. Laws against “buggery” were frequently used to arrest individuals for this crime. Ireland was the first country to legalize this crime by the popular vote. Two years after being convicted for this crime, a war hero ate a cyanide-laced apple to commit suicide. Alan Turing was prosecuted for, for ten points, what romantic crime?",
      "answer": [
        "homosexuality",
        "equivalents, such as being gay",
        "sodomy",
        "buggery before mentioned"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "The creation of this route was documented in the Kaiheji. Older predecessors of this route include the Hong Gou and Han Gou. The city of Kaifeng became a major commercial hub due to this route. Disruptions along this route could be seen as a loss of the Mandate of Heaven. Work on this route began during the Spring and Autumn Period, and it was fully connected during the Sui Dynasty to ship grain and expedite trade. For ten points, name this great work of Chinese infrastructure that starts in Beijing and connects the Yellow and Yangtze Rivers, the longest canal in the world.",
      "answer": "Beijing-Hangzhou Grand Canal"
    },
    {
      "question": "A controversially ugly skyscraper in this city stands at 30 St. Mary Axe and is nicknamed for its similarity to a type of pickle. Renzo Piano designed a skyscraper in this city’s Southwark borough known as The Shard. A landmark known as this city’s Eye was built to commemorate the millennium in 2000; that Ferris wheel became a common sight in television coverage of the 2012 Summer Olympics. For ten points, name this city whose less modern architecture includes Westminster Palace, the meeting place of British Parliament.",
      "answer": "London"
    },
    {
      "question": "A claim involving this woman was popularized by a 1974 biography written by Fawn M. Brodie and was further developed in the late 20th and early 21st centuries by Annette Gordon-Reed. This woman’s children, including Beverley, Madison, and Eston, have no records of a second parent in a contemporary Farm Book. This woman accompanied the girl Polly to live in France for five years beginning in 1784. For ten points, name this slave who probably had several children with Thomas Jefferson.",
      "answer": "Sally Hemings"
    },
    {
      "question": "This author used the couplet “Ready, be ready to meet the storm! / Riflemen, riflemen, riflemen form!” to end all four stanzas of his poem “The War.” In another poem by this author, a group travels to, and then back from, the “mouth of hell.” That poem by this author asks “Was there a man dismay’d?” because a group of soldiers are unaware of a blunder made by their commander. For ten points, name this poet who wrote about a doomed assault made by six hundred cavalrymen in “The Charge of the Light Brigade.”",
      "answer": "Alfred, Lord Tennyson"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first time that Rome attacked Illyria was meant to stop a supporter of these people named Teuta. These people were supposed to help guide the slaves of Spartacus to safety, but deserted them prior to the Battle of the Siler River. Pompey was granted great powers to fight these people in the Lex Gabinia, and a number of these people were crucified after they held a young Julius Caesar for ransom. Cilicia was a Roman-era stronghold of, for ten points, what seafaring marauders?",
      "answer": "pirates"
    },
    {
      "question": "Suetonius noted how this figure owned a “collar of stones” and a “troop of slaves and furniture.” To disprove a prophecy made by Thrasyllus of Mendes, grain barges were used to create a bridge across the Bay of Baiae for this figure to travel on. This figure, who had a name meaning “swift,” was owned by the brother of Drusilla; because that man was assassinated in 41 AD, this figure never ended up becoming consul. For ten points, name this horse that was beloved by Caligula.",
      "answer": "Incitatus"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first member of this group wrote a poetry collection, Asa di Var, that was compiled by another member of this group, Arjan Dev. The tenth member of this group initiated the five Panj Pyare into the Khalsa. Members of this group include Amar Das and a man born Gobind Rai. The final member of this group is, and will eternally be, the Adi Granth, a religious text. Nanak was the first of, for ten points, what group of 11 sources of guidance for Sikhs?",
      "answer": "Sikh gurus"
    },
    {
      "question": "One holder of this position tried to stop Richard Olney from stopping the Pullman Strike. John Peter Altgeld held this position in the 19th century, while Otto Kerner and George Ryan held it in the 20th century. While serving in this position, Rod Blagojevich [blah-goy-eh-vich] was arrested for corruption related to the “sale” of President-elect Obama’s vacated Senate seat. Bruce Rauner currently holds, for ten points, what leadership position in the “Land of Lincoln?”",
      "answer": "Governor of Illinois"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Alexander Neckham’s On the Nature of Things provides the earliest European account of these devices. The Dream Pool Essays describes how wax was attached to the center of a component of these devices that was then hung from a strain of silk. These devices, which were originally used for divination in feng shui, are one of the Four Great Inventions of China, and they were adapted for maritime use to provide direction during cloudy weather. For ten points, name this navigational device that contains a magnetic needle.",
        "answer": "compass"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Early compasses worked by suspending one of these rocks, as described in The Dream Pool Essays. These magnetized hunks of magnetite attract iron, though the process by which these rocks become magnetized isn’t known.",
        "answer": "lodestones"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In this election year, James Farley resigned from a cabinet post after placing second in a party nomination vote. After losing in this election year, a major candidate allegedly engaged in an affair with Chiang Kai-Shek’s wife. Roger Babson ran on the Prohibition Party ticket in this election, whose vice-presidential winner later ran with Glen Taylor in 1948 on the Progressive Party ticket. Henry Wallace became vice president in, for ten points, what election year that ushered in Franklin Delano Roosevelt’s third term?",
        "answer": "United States Presidential Election of 1940"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This lawyer won 82 electoral votes as the Republican nominee in 1940. After the election, this man worked as an informal representative to the UK for Roosevelt.",
        "answer": "Wendell Willkie"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man’s most famous advisor broke off his teeth to assure his mother that power would not change him. Though this man may have assassinated the satraps Nicanor and Philip, he received the Greek ambassador Megasthenes and influenced the Battle of Ipsus by giving 300 war elephants to Seleucus. This man allegedly met his end by fasting to death in a Jain ceremony. The Arthashastra was written by Kautilya an advisor to this man. For ten points, name this ruler who, as a teenager, defeated the Nanda dynasty to unite India and found the Mauryan empire.",
        "answer": "Chandragupta Maurya"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Chandragupta was succeeded by this monarch, who was named for the drop of poison atop his head. This monarch in turn fathered Ashoka.",
        "answer": "Bindusara"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The first of Peter Hebblethwaite’s two papal biographies focuses on this man. Sedevacantism holds that the last valid pope was succeeded by this man. This pope issued a bull addressed to “all men of good will” that advocated for nuclear non-proliferation. This author of Pacem in Terris and successor to Pius XII convened a council that produced the Dignitatus Humanae and allowed for the mass to be performed in the vernacular. For ten points, name this pope who convened the Second Vatican Council in 1959.",
        "answer": [
          "Pope Saint John XXIII",
          "Ioannes XXIII",
          "Giovanni XXIII",
          "Angelo Giuseppe Roncalli"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "John XXIII hailed from this region of Italy. Its people were led by Desiderius in medieval times.",
        "answer": [
          "Lombardy",
          "Lombardia"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A painting created and set in this city shows a woman in a black dress shielding her eyes from a doctor making an incision in a patient’s thigh. This city was the home of Thomas Eakins, who painted The Gross Clinic. Another painting set in this city shows Roger Sherman, Robert Livingston, and Thomas Jefferson presenting the title document to John Hancock. For ten points, name this city where John Trumbull’s Declaration of Independence is set.",
        "answer": "Philadelphia"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "A museum dedicated to this sculptor is part of the Philadelphia Museum of Art. Its collections feature casts of his sculpture of Honore de Balzac.",
        "answer": "Auguste Rodin"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In response to revelations regarding NSA surveillance, this country’s leader said that “the Internet is uncharted territory for us all.” Former President of European Parliament Martin Schulz announced his intentions to run as the Social Democratic Candidate in October 2017 elections in this country. Recep Erdogan [aird-oh-wan] accused this country of “Nazi practices” after pro-Erdogan rallies were cancelled in Frechen and Cologne. For ten points, name this country led by the Christian Democratic Union under Chancellor Angela Merkel.",
        "answer": "Germany or Deutschland"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Another German political party running in the October 2017 Bundestag elections is this right-wing Eurosceptic party, which has criticized Merkel’s decision to grant asylum to hundreds of thousands of migrants. It is currently led by Frauke Petry.",
        "answer": "Alternative fur Deutschland or Alternative for Germany"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This treaty was signed by one side after it received a final death blow in an eleven-day offensive named Operation Fist Punch. To reverse a result from 1877, a provision transferring Ardahan and Batumi was added into this treaty at the request of Talaat Pasha. The Treaty of Rapallo finally annulled this treaty, which failed to set up an independent Ukraine state and ceded the Baltic States to Germany. Leon Trotsky accepted this treaty on behalf of the Bolsheviks. For ten points, name this 1918 treaty that took Russia out of World War I.",
        "answer": "Treaty of Brest-Litovsk"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Another harsh treaty of World War I was this 1920 treaty that stripped Hungary of two-thirds of its pre-war territory.",
        "answer": "Treaty of Trianon"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man names a fort that was used by runaway slaves in the Florida Panhandle. As president of the South Carolina Railroad, this man advocated for the construction of a southern transcontinental railway route. While serving as an ambassador, this man oversaw the negotiation of a ten million dollar agreement to acquire lands south of the Gila River. For ten points, identify this diplomat who names an 1853 purchase of land from Mexico.",
        "answer": "James Gadsden"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This Secretary of War under Franklin Pierce lobbied for the ratification of the Gadsden Purchase in Congress. This man later served as a senator from Mississippi, among other political positions.",
        "answer": "Jefferson Davis"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "Theodore Roosevelt",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Type of woodland animal he refused to shoot, inspiring the name of a stuffed toy.",
          "answer": [
            "bear",
            "Teddy bear"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Political party he ran for President with in 1912.",
          "answer": "Progressive Party or Bull Moose Party"
        },
        {
          "question": "Swedish award he won for negotiating an end to the Russo-Japanese War.",
          "answer": "Nobel Peace Prize"
        },
        {
          "question": "Midwestern city where he was shot in 1912 while giving a speech.",
          "answer": "Milwaukee"
        },
        {
          "question": "1906 act he passed supposedly after reading The Jungle.",
          "answer": [
            "Pure Food and Drug Act, Bill,",
            "Law"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Naval expedition he sent to circumnavigate the world in 1907.",
          "answer": "Great White Fleet"
        },
        {
          "question": "Industry whose rebates Roosevelt fined with the 1903 Elkins Act.",
          "answer": "railroad industry"
        },
        {
          "question": "Symbol he made in his diary after the death of his mother and wife.",
          "answer": "an X"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Historians",
      "prompt": "What historian...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Won the 1953 Literature Nobel for his work on the Second World War, during which he was Prime Minister of Britain?",
          "answer": "Winston Churchill"
        },
        {
          "question": "Wrote about his own military campaigns in his Commentaries on the Gallic War?",
          "answer": "Gaius Julius Caesar"
        },
        {
          "question": "Blamed Christianity in his monumental History of the Decline and Fall of the Roman Empire?",
          "answer": "Edward Gibbon"
        },
        {
          "question": "Wrote a history of Rome titled Ab Urbe Condita that was the subject of “Discourses” by Machiavelli?",
          "answer": "Livy or Titus Livius"
        },
        {
          "question": "Wrote about his father-in-law’s experiences in Britannia in Agricola?",
          "answer": [
            "Gaius",
            "Publius Cornelius Tacitus"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Bizarrely claimed that, in India, there are fox-sized ants that dig up gold?",
          "answer": "Herodotus"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "about the Roman Republic?",
      "prompt": "What...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Italian explorer landed in the Caribbean in 1492?",
          "answer": "Christopher Columbus"
        },
        {
          "question": "Engineering project was not built by Frenchman Ferdinand de Lesseps and was built by Americans in former Colombia?",
          "answer": "Panama Canal"
        },
        {
          "question": "Island provided Catholic immigrants, such as the father of Bernardo O’Higgins?",
          "answer": "Ireland"
        },
        {
          "question": "Spanish Conquistador conquered the Incas?",
          "answer": "Francisco Pizarro Gonz´alez"
        },
        {
          "question": "Failed country saw some of its citizens move to Brazil because it still accepted slavery in 1865?",
          "answer": [
            "Confederate States of America or CSA",
            "Confederacy"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Second generation Japanese-Peruvian leader cracked down on the Shining Path?",
          "answer": "Alberto Fujimori"
        },
        {
          "question": "Ethnic group established a colony in Patagonia called Y Wladfa [uh LAHD-fah]?",
          "answer": "Welsh or Cymry"
        },
        {
          "question": "Term referred to Spanish-born people in the New World, who had higher status than American-born creoles?",
          "answer": "peninsulares"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) A piece of music depicting this city calls for six buccina, though flugelhorns are normally used. A carnival in this city was the subject of a concert overture adapted from Benvenuto Cellini by Hector Berlioz. Another work depicting this city includes a recording of a (20 pts)",
        "nightingale in its “Janiculum” section. This city titled a French scholarship that was abolished in 1968 and entitled the winner to stay at the (10 pts)",
        "Villa Medici. For ten points, a work depicting the “Pines” of what city, by Ottorino Respighi, ends with a depiction of legions marching down the Appian Way?"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Rome",
        "Pines of Rome",
        "Prix de Rome"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man adopted the name John Hume Ross so that he could join the RAF without fanfare. The Battle of Maysaloun undid the provisional government of the Emir Faisal, which had been set up by this man. He was captured at (20 pts)",
        "Daraa while under the command of Edmund Allenby. This man worked with Auda ibu Tayi in seizing Aqaba shortly after being sent to reconnoiter the (10 pts)",
        "Hejaz. In 1918, this man captured Damascus from the Ottoman Empire, an event recounted in his autobiographical Seven Pillars of Wisdom. For ten points, name this British leader of the Arab Revolt during World War I."
      ],
      "answer": "Thomas Edward Lawrence or Lawrence of Arabia"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) During this battle, Thomas Duplessis placed his cannons on Combs Hill. After this battle, British forces marched toward Sandy Hook. An unwanted retreat at this battle resulted in the court martial of (20 pts)",
        "Charles Lee. 37 Americans died from heat stroke during this battle, during which temperatures reached above 100 degrees Fahrenheit. A (10 pts)",
        "woman known as Mary Hays legendarily brought water to the troops as a result of the heat, earning the nickname of “Molly Pitcher.” For ten points, name this 1778 Revolutionary War battle in New Jersey."
      ],
      "answer": "Battle of Monmouth Courthouse"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The Northcote-Trevelyan Report praised this system and urged the development of one similar to it in England. These events are criticized in “The Seven Likenesses of a Candidate,” which mocks participants awaiting their results as “chimpanzees in captivity.” Participants in these events often (20 pts)",
        "wore underwear with quotes from the classics written on them, which needed to be exactly quoted for the eight-legged essay. After failing these events four times, (10 pts)",
        "Hong Xiuquan launched the Taiping Rebellion. For ten points, name this meritocratic system that selected Chinese bureaucrats for more than two thousand years."
      ],
      "answer": "imperial Chinese civil service examinations or keju"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man worked to distribute American surplus internationally as the first director of “Food for Peace.” This man worked with Donald Fraser to establish a commission increasing the number of caucuses and primaries. Along with Mark (20 pts)",
        "Hatfield, this man attempted to propose legislation ending the Vietnam War. After running mate Thomas Eagleton was discovered to have undergone (10 pts)",
        "electric shock therapy, this presidential candidate carried only Massachusetts. For ten points, name this South Dakota senator who lost the 1972 presidential election to Richard Nixon."
      ],
      "answer": "George McGovern"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The “First Principles” of this amendment were attacked by Akhil Amar in an essay calling this amendment “an embarrassment.” Edward Coke’s decision in Semayne’s case led to this amendment’s inclusion. The (20 pts)",
        "plain-view and “open-fields” doctrines are used in cases involving this amendment. The “fruit of the forbidden tree” rule expands this amendment’s (10 pts)",
        "“exclusionary rule,” which applied to the states after Mapp v. Ohio. For ten points, name this amendment of the Constitution that prohibits the issuance of warrants without probable cause, as well as unreasonable searches and seizures."
      ],
      "answer": "4th Amendment to the U.S. Constitution"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This actor starred in a film based on Daisy Suckley’s diaries; in that film, 2012’s Hyde Park on Hudson, this man played FDR. This actor tried speaking English with a Nazi as Richard Campbell in The Monuments Men. After the 2016 (20 pts)",
        "World Series, this actor sneaked in to honk the horn of MVP Ben Zobrist’s new car. This actor’s only Oscar nomination came in 2003 for playing Bob Harris in (10 pts)",
        "Lost in Translation. For ten points, name this actor whose less historic and more comedic roles include Carl Spackler and Dr. Peter Venkman in Caddyshack and Ghostbusters, respectively."
      ],
      "answer": "William James “Bill” Murray"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) An army withdrew from this conflict when Raymond II was suspected of poisoning Alfonso Jordan. The Council of Acre [AH-kreh] was convened before an ill-advised attack through an orchard in the decisive battle of this conflict. (20 pts)",
        "Bernard of Clairvaux helped drum up support for this conflict, which was prompted by Zengi’s capture of Edessa. This conflict ended with Baldwin III of (10 pts)",
        "Jerusalem’s unsuccessful siege of Damascus. Pope Eugene III initiated, for ten points, what religious campaign, fifty years after Urban II called for its precursor?"
      ],
      "answer": "Second Crusade"
    }
  ]
}